Guide to the Dwight W. Edwards Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Dwight W. Edwards Papers
1905-1982
RG 12
Yale University Divinity School Library
8
(19 boxes)
The papers document Dwight W. Edwards' work in China, particularly with the YMCA in Peking, which was sponsored by the Princeton University Student Christian Association. The famine relief work of various organizations in China is also well documented. Edwards was a missionary in China from 1906 to 1949. He was active in YMCA work, particularly in Peking, and in famine relief work throughout China from 1920 to 1949. Edwards held leadership positions with the China International Famine Relief Commission, United China Relief, and United Service to China, and was also associated with Yenching University in Peking.
Edwards, Dwight W. (Dwight Woodbridge), 1883-1967
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Anne and Robert Brank Fulton, 1982, 1983.
Biographical / Historical
1883Mar 25 Born in St. Paul, Minnesota, son of Rev. Maurice and Annie Edwards.
1904 B.A., cum laude, Princeton University.
1905 M.A., in mathematics, Princeton University.
1905-1906 Teacher in Japan under YMCA auspices.
1906-1946 Served YMCA in China.
1906-1924 Associate general secretary of Peking YMCA. Peking YMCA was sponsored by Princeton-in-Peking, which later became the Princeton-Yenching Foundation
1915 Married Mary E. Vanderslice, ABCFM missionary serving as Director of Kindergarten Training in the North China College for Women. Children: Dwight W., Jr. and Anne.
1920-1922 Executive secretary of Peking United International Famine Relief Committee. This relief operation resulted in the formation of the China International Famine Relief Commission, which functioned from 1922 to 1946 in relief and prevention of famine in China.
1920-1922 Executive secretary of Finance Commission of the Government Relief Bureau administering the Surtax on the Maritime Customs for Relief.
1922-1950 Executive field secretary of Princeton-Yenching Foundation.
1925-1927 General secretary of Peking YMCA following retirement of Robert Gailey, until Chinese General secretary was appointed.
1927-1938 YMCA Regional secretary for North China, based in Peking.
1931 Six months service with Chinese Government Yangtze flood relief work.
1932-1948 Member of the Board of Managers of Yenching University.
1938-1946 YMCA Senior secretary in China, based first in Shanghai and from 1941 to 1946 in Chungking.
1942-1946 Field Director and Vice-president of United China Relief (later known as United Service to China), on loan from YMCA.
1943, 1946 Received Chinese government awards for relief and educational work.
1946-1949 Full time work for United Service to China following retirement from YMCA.
1948 Executive secretary of the Administrative Committee of Yenching University.
1949 Honorary Doctorate of Philanthropy, Princeton University.
1949 Returned from China to the U.S., continued to serve as consultant in relief field for several years.
1959 DWE's monograph, Yenching University, published by United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia.
1967 Oct 4 Died in Princeton, New Jersey.
Scope and Contents
I. Correspondence, 1924-1965, n.d.
II. Addresses, articles, reports, 1909-1959.
III. Yenching monograph, 1956, n.d.
IV. Notes, ca. 1912-1949.
V. Collected material, ca. 1905-1965, n.d.
VI. Personal items and memorabilia, 1918-1982, n.d.
Dwight W. Edwards spent more than forty years serving the Chinese people in educational and relief work. The small group of papers in this record group cannot do full justice to the extent and depth of Edwards' contributions, but these papers do reflect the wide range of his activities, and are particularly valuable for their documentation of the Peking YMCA, Princeton-in-Peking, Yenching University, and the famine relief work of United China Relief and its successor, United Service to China. Edwards' correspondence, writings, and notes, as well as the printed material that he collected, all shed light on his philosophy and methods of work.
The correspondence of Series I consists primarily of letters related to various aspects of Edwards' professional activities in China. There are letters of a more personal nature from the period following his retirement, but virtually no family correspondence. Of special interest are letters exchanged with representatives of organizations involved in relief work, letters documenting squabbles within the missionary ranks (particularly surrounding Robert Gailey in 1924, and W.B. Pettus in 1927), and letters received from William Kelly and Ralph Lapwood (1951-1957) that describe life in China following the Communist takeover.
The addresses, articles, and reports of Series II reflect the spectrum of Edwards' interests. Edwards' analyses of the political and religious situation in China include well-informed descriptions of the tumultuous events that occurred between 1906 and 1949. A small number of papers deal specifically with the anti-Christian movement in China in the early 1920s. Writings related to famine relief include detailed on-site reports and broader overviews. Writings related to the YMCA, Princeton-in-Peking, and the Princeton-Yenching Foundation have been grouped together because of their interrelatedness in Edwards' career. Many annual reports written by Edwards are included in this section.
Series III includes notes and drafts used in the preparation of Edwards' book, Yenching University. Correspondence related to Edwards' efforts to gather information and advice for this historical work is found in Series I.
Edwards' notes in Series IV relate to many of the same topics as his writings but are more fragmentary in nature. Of particular interest are detailed notes describing Edwards' work among Chinese laborers in France during World War I.
Series V contains primarily printed or typescript material related to various organizations and topics. Little of this material is rare or unique, but it is of value for defining the context of Edwards' work. Annual reports of the china International Famine Relief Commission for the years 1923-1934 are included, as well as significant documentation of the Princeton work in China, and United Service to China.
Series VI includes scattered documentation of Edwards' activities and background. Most noteworthy is a manuscript entitled "The Mission to China of Dwight Woodbridge and Mary Vanderslice Edwards" written by Edwards' son-in-law, Robert Brank Fulton, in 1982.
The Edwards Papers were given to the Yale Divinity School Library in June 1982 and January 1983 by his daughter and son-in-law, Anne and Robert Brank Fulton. A number of Chinese language periodicals and pamphlets received with the papers were transferred to the East Asian Collection of the Yale University Library.
The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by writer or recipient other than DWE. In most cases letters are filed under a personal rather than corporate name. Cross references will alert the researcher to correspondence related to organizations that is filed under a personal name. Folders labeled with letters only, such as "Ad-Al", are followed by individual folders for more prominent or frequent correspondents. One folder of first names only and unidentified correspondence concludes the series.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1924-1965, n.d.
II. Addresses, articles, reports, 1909-1959
III. Yenching monograph, 1956, n.d.
IV. Notes, ca. 1912-1949
V. Collected material, ca. 1905-1965, n.d.
VI. Personal items and memorabilia, 1918-1982, n.d.
Disaster relief -- China; Missions -- China; Young Men's Christian Associations; Missionaries; Edwards, Dwight Woodbridge; Gamble, Sidney D. (Sidney David), 1890-1968; Lapwood, E. R.; China International Famine Relief Commission; Princeton University Center in China; United China Relief (U.S.); United Service to China, Inc; Yanjing da xue
- Correspondence, 1924-1965, n.d.; Series I
  - Ad-Al (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Am (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - An-Au (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adolph, William H., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - B (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Barnett, Eugene E., 1927-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Burgess, J. Stewart, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ca-Cha (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Che-Chr (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chu-Cl (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Co-Cu (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chang Hung-chun, 1946-1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Childs, John L., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - China International Famine Relief Commission, 1951-1964 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - China Mainland Famine Relief Association, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Chuan, S.J. (Jimmy), 1946-1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Chuan, Victor, 1951-1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Church World Service ( see Birkel, A. Henry; Henry, Robert T.; Vaught, Arnold B.)
  - D (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Dsang, Y.S., 1929-1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Duff, James H., 1946-1954 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Dulles, Allen, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - E (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - F (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Fenn,William P. ( see: Princeton-Yenching Foundation; United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia)
  - G (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Gailey, Robert, 1924-1950 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Gamble, Sidney ( see also: Princeton-Yenching Foundation), 1933-1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Garside, B.A., 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Garside, B.A., 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Ha (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - He - Ho (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Hs - Hu (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Henry, Robert T., 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Henry, Robert T., 1950 Jan-Jul (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Henry, Robert T., 1950 Aug-Sep (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Henry, Robert T., 1950 Oct-Dec (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Henry, Robert T., 1951-1964 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Hibben, John G., 1932 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Hull, Cordell, 1942, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - I (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - International Relief Committee of China ( see: Dsang, Y.S.)
  - J (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - K (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Kelly, William, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Kelly, William, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Kelly, William, 1955-1957, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - La - Le (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Li - Lu (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Lapwood, Ralph, 1951-1952 Oct (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Lapwood, Ralph, 1952 Nov - 1953, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Leung, Siu choh, 1951-1961 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Ly, J. Usang, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - M (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - McClelland, Dalton F., 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - McCracken, Josiah C., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - McMullen, Robert J. ( seealso: United Board), 1954 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Mass Education Movement (James Y.C. Chen)
  - ( see: Chang, H.C.; Chen (?), C.C.; Djang, Y.S.
  - Mei, Y. P., 1949-1952 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Mei, Y. P., 1953-1958 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Merwin, Wallace C. ( see also: NCCCUSA, DFM; Presbyterian Board of Foreign Missions, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Mott, John R., 1949, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - N (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - National Council of Churches of Christ in the U.S.A., Division of Foreign Missions, 1954-1960 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - National Red Cross Society of China, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - National Student Relief Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - North China Language School (re. Pettus squabble, 1927) ( see: Barnett, Eugene; Herschleb, C.A.; March, B.; Smith, Dennis; Wilder, George; Yui, David Z.T.
  - O (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - P (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Pai, T.S. and Charles, 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Peking Y.M.C.A. (re. Gailey squabble, 1924) ( see: Burgess, J.S.; Gailey, Robert; Princeton-Yenching Foundation; Sweet, Lennig)
  - Princeton-Yenching Foundation ( see also: Gamble, Sidney), 1949-1957 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Pyle, Stephen, 1949-1957 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Q, R (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Sa - Sc (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Se - Sh (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Si - Sw (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Sailer, Randolph, 1949-1959 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - ShÉ, Louise, 1949-1951 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Stuart, J. Leighton, 1954, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Sweet, Lennig, 1924-1964, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - T (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - U (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - United Board for Christian Colleges in China, 1948-1954 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - UBCCC and UBCHEA/ corres. with C. Corbett re. Yenching monograph, 1952-1959 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - United China Relief ( see: Chu You-kuang; Fitch, George; Freeman, Mansfield; Hsu, K. M.; Little, L. K.; Sweet, Lennig; Young, Arthur)
  - United Service to China ( see also: Barnett, E.; Chu You-kuang; Chuan, S. J.; Freeman, M.; Garside, B.A.; Henry, Robert T.; United Board C.C.C.; Veryard, Robert), 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration ( see: Fitch, George)
  - Vaught, Arnold b., 1949-1953 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Veryard, Robert, 1947-1949 Aug (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Veryard, Robert, 1949 Sep - 1950 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - W (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Wanamaker, O.D., 1924, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Wiant, Bliss, 1948-1957 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Wilder, George D., 1927 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Y (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Yui, David Z. T., 1927 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Zia, Nai-zing, 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Unidentified (Box 5, Folder 86)
- Addresses, Articles, Reports, 1909-1959; Series II
  - Analyses of China situation, ca. 1911-1918 (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Analyses of China situation, ca. 1919-ca. 1926 (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - Analyses of China situation, 1930s (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Analyses of China situation, 1940s (Box 6, Folder 90)
  - Analyses of China situation, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - Anti-Christian movement in China, 1922-ca. 1925 (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - Biographical sketches
    - Djang Bo Ling and Ding Li Mei, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Fenn, Courtney H., 1920s (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Fenn, William P., 1959 (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Gailey, Robert, 1950, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - Lowrie, Walter, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - Wilbur, Hollis, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Famine relief, ca. 1920-1921 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - Famine relief, ca. 1925-1929 (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Famine relief, ca. 1931-1933 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - Famine relief, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Famine relief, 1942-ca. 1943, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - YMCA/ Princeton-in-Peking/ Princeton-Yenching Foundation
    - Annual reports, 1907, 1908, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - "Tungchou Summer Conference", 1909 (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - Annual reports, 1910, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - re. summer conference, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - re. Princeton work, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - Annual reports, 1912, 1913, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - "The Paths Made Straight", ca. 1912 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - "The Realization of a Vision", ca. 1914 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - Annual reports, 1916, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - "The Returned Student Work", 1917 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - "China and Princeton", ca. 1917 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Annual reports, 1918, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Annual report, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - Annual report, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - Statements re. Peking work, ca. 1922 (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - "Peking Young Men of 1922-1923" (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - Newsletters, reports, 1926-1928 (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - "Report of North China Region", ca. 1931 (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - Newsletter, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - "Report of Visit to Tatungfu, Shansi", 1932 (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - Administrative report, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 111)
    - "General Situation", 1930s (Box 8, Folder 111)
    - Annual report, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 112)
    - re. Princeton-Yenching Rural Demonstration Center at Ching-Ho, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - "Report on Trip of Inspection to Suiyuan", 1936 (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - Newsletter, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - "The Journey Continued from Lanchow", 1941 (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - "Report of visitation of YMCAs in Northwest", 1941 (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - "Report on a Trip to Mukden", ca. 1942 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - Statement, reports, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - "Christianity and Commerce" (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - "Confidence in the Association", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - "The First Summer Conference in North China", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - "The Fourth Summer Conference...", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - re. Peking Thrift Society, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - "The Returned Student", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - "The YMCA ini War Time China", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Miscellaneous
    - "A Wild in China", 1916 (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - "Light That is Darkness", 1933 (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - "The Livelihood of Missionaries", 1929 (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - "Present Day Democracy", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - Sermon on Mark 10: 13-16, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - "The Way to Peace", 1951 (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - Untitled, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 119)
- Yenching Monograph, 1956, n.d.; Series III
  - Early handwritten drafts (Box 10, Folder 120-123)
  - Early typescript drafts, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Draft of Section II, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Draft of Section III, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Draft of Section V, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - Preliminary version of Sections I and II, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - Notes, source material, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 129-130)
  - Card file, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 131-133)
- Notes, 1912-1949; Series IV
  - British labor movement, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 134)
  - Chinese laborers in France, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 135)
  - Japan, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - Map of famine area, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - Peking University 1890-1922, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - Peking YMCA / Princeton-in-Peking, ca. 1912, 1918, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 138)
  - Religious topics, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 139)
  - Religious topics, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 140)
  - Study notes in A Harmony of the Gospels by Stevens and Burton (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - "The Syncretic Mind in Chinese Religious Life" (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - United Service to China, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - Young Adult Bible Class, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - Unidentified, 1943, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 143)
- Collected Material, 1905-1965, n.d.; Series V
  - Organizations
    - American Aid to China, 1949 Jan-Feb (Box 13, Folder 144)
    - American Aid to China, 1949 Mar-Apr (Box 13, Folder 145)
    - American Institute of Foreign Relations, 1950-1953 (Box 13, Folder 146)
    - American Institute of Foreign Relations, 1954-1960 (Box 13, Folder 147)
    - Association for the Advancement of the Chinese Industrial Cooperatives, 1946, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 148)
    - California College in China, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 149)
    - China Institute in America, 1949-1962 (Box 13, Folder 150)
    - China International Famine Relief Commission ( see also: International Relief Committee of China), 1923-1925 (Box 13, Folder 151)
    - China International Famine Relief Commission ( see also: International Relief Committee of China), 1926-1929 (Box 13, Folder 152)
    - China International Famine Relief Commission ( see also: International Relief Committee of China), 1930-1933 (Box 14, Folder 153)
    - China International Famine Relief Commission ( see also: International Relief Committee of China), 1934-1936 (Box 14, Folder 154)
    - China International Famine Relief Commission ( see also: International Relief Committee of China), 1937-1949 (Box 14, Folder 155)
    - China Nutritional Aid Council, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 156)
    - Chinese National Association of the Mass Education Movement, 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 157)
    - Chinese People's Relief Commission, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 158)
    - Church World Service - China office, 1948-1950 Jun (Box 14, Folder 159)
    - Church World Service - China office, 1950 Jul-Sep (Box 14, Folder 160)
    - Economic Cooperation Administration, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 161)
    - International Relief Committee of China, 1949-1950 (Box 14, Folder 162)
    - The Je-Nao-Faculty Dramatic Club, Yenching University, 1921-1928 (Box 15, Folder 163)
    - National Flood Relief Commission, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 164)
    - National Student Relief Commission, ca. 1949 (Box 15, Folder 165)
    - National War Work Council of China, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 166)
    - New Life Movement, Women's Advisory Council, 1943-1948 (Box 15, Folder 166)
    - Old Guard of Princeton, 1957-1965 (Box 15, Folder 167)
    - Peking Union Church (reunion), 1954-1955 (Box 15, Folder 167)
    - Peking YMCA ( see: Princeton-in-Peking)
    - Princeton-in-Peking / Princeton-Yenching Foundation, ca. 1905-1916 (Box 15, Folder 168)
    - Princeton-in-Peking / Princeton-Yenching Foundation, 1917-1923 (Box 15, Folder 169)
    - Princeton-in-Peking / Princeton-Yenching Foundation, 1924-1926 (Box 15, Folder 170)
    - Princeton-in-Peking / Princeton-Yenching Foundation, 1927-1952 (Box 15, Folder 171)
    - Princeton-in-Peking / Princeton-Yenching Foundation, 1953-1958 (Box 16, Folder 172)
    - Princeton-in-Peking / Princeton-Yenching Foundation (Box 16, Folder 173)
    - Princeton Leadership Training School, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 174)
    - Rotary Club of Shanghai, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 174)
    - Shanghai Federation for Emergency Relief, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 175)
    - Tsing Hua Dramatic Club, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 176)
    - United China Relief ( see also: United Service to China), ca. 1945 (Box 16, Folder 177)
    - United Nations, 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 178)
    - United Service to China, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 179)
    - United Service to China, 1949 Jan-Mar (Box 16, Folder 180)
    - United Service to China, 1949 Apr-Jul (Box 16, Folder 181)
    - United Service to China, 1949 Aug-Dec (Box 16, Folder 182)
    - United Service to China, 1950 Jan-May (Box 16, Folder 183)
    - United Service to China, 1950 Jun-1951, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 184)
    - United Service to China - Fundraising information, 1941-1950 (Box 17, Folder 185)
    - Yenching Alumni Association, 1951-1959 (Box 17, Folder 186)
    - Yenching University, 1949, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 187)
    - YMCAs of China and Korea, 1912, 1917, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 188)
    - YMCA - World Service Fellowship, 1952-1954 (Box 17, Folder 189)
  - Topics
    - Arms race, 1960, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 190)
    - Asia - political and religious situation, 1934, 1953, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 191)
    - China - Chinese philosophy (Y. P. Mei), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 192)
    - China - Collection of statistical information from china Christian colleges (C. T. Liu), 1949 (Box 17, Folder 193)
    - China - David Z. T. Yui, 1926 (Box 18, Folder 194)
    - China - political and religious situation, 1916-1925 (Box 18, Folder 195)
    - China - political and religious situation, 1926-1927 (Box 18, Folder 196)
    - China - political and religious situation, 1928-1941 (Box 18, Folder 197)
    - China - political and religious situation, 1945-1949 (Box 18, Folder 198)
    - China - political and religious situation, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 199)
    - China - political and religious situation, 1951-1955 (Box 18, Folder 200)
    - China - political and religious situation, 1956-1958 (Box 18, Folder 201)
    - China - political and religious situation, 1959-1964 (Box 18, Folder 202)
    - China - political and religious situation (Box 18, Folder 203)
    - China - famine relief and social welfare work, 1921, 1949, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 204)
    - Chinese laborers in France, 1919 (Box 18, Folder 205)
    - Miscellaneous, 1927, 1937, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 206)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1918-1982, n.d.; Series VI
  - Address book (Box 19, Folder 207)
  - Biographical documentation, 1918-1938 (Box 19, Folder 208)
  - Biographical documentation, 1943-1949 (Box 19, Folder 209)
  - Biographical documentation, 1951-1967 (Box 19, Folder 210)